I told you,
I ain't ever been caught
and I ain't ever gonna be caught.
Psychopras.
Put up a roadblock. Hold on.
Ain't no way me and Mr. Bear
are going to the big house.
No, Maam.
Daddy, go faster.
- Hi, Mrs. Akers. Hi, Florence.
- Why, hello, Penny.
What's going on over there?
Daddy's putting the car up on
block so we can save money on gas.
Oh, well, isn't that smart?
Mr. Murphy, I've been mean to ask.
Our car has been acting real funny,
and I thought maybe
if you're not too busy,
maybe you might take a look.
Ed says, you know more than
any mechanic in town,
so I sure would appreciate it. And.
And of course, we'll pay you for your time.
- She pay you lots of money?
- No.
- How come?
- Cause her car wasn't broke.
You could have broken it for her
and then fixed it.
I thought about that.
Do you know how to do that?
Maybe she'll go next door and
ask Mrs. Akers to help.
Are you kidding me?
This is your father you're talking to.
Like I need Mrs. Akers.
Girl, I've made planes fly.
I can rebuild an engine, frame a house.
Shoot, I made you.
You think I don't know how...
How to mend a sock?
Doesn't look like it.
We will be tested.
But as the psalmist David writes
on this occasion, wait on the Lord.
Be of good courage,
and he shall strengthen the heart.
Wait, I say. On the Lord.
Let us pray.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, Thy will be
done on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our debts,
as we forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom
and the power
and the glory,
forever and ever.
Amen.
But why has it
gotta be so boring?
Well, they want to bore the
devil out of little girls, I guess.
Your mother used to sleep
through the whole service.
Pastor was like warm milk.
She said
Hey...
Get this stuff out of your way.
That is a terrible thing, Sam.
Evict a man while he's at church.
That's terrible thing.
Do you have a place where you can go?
Yeah. We've got a plan.
If you want to have stuff, you can have it.
If it's okay and you're
not planning on taking it,
we sure would like to buy that
radio from you.
I've been meaning to buy a portable
one, and that one's just perfect.
Yeah, thank you.
It's great. Sure.
No, son, that's Penny's bear.
That's not for sale.
- Yes, he is.
- No, he's not.
It's okay, Daddy.
I don't need him anymore.
I want you to have him.
Stop kicking.
I told you, I'll buy him back.
I'll go there right now and buy him back.
Look, it's what you said you wanted.
Well, you said you wanted
to sell Mama's radio.
Look, I think I found us the perfect place.
It's right by your school.
You're still gonna go
to school, aren't you?
You're not gonna run
off and join the circus?
Start working with elephants, huh?
No, school's okay.
Look, I didn't really like that old
apartment anyway.
We should try this new place, you know,
Give it a week. See if we like it.
I mean, it's a good neighborhood.
Give a nice loud knock.
Yeah. Good job.
Hallo.
Come here.
Careful for the glass.
All right. Have a seat.
Maybe look up that other address
you found. Okay.
Look your best, will you?
Hello?
Hello. Hey,
- what you doing down there?
- Oh, well,
my daughter and I are
looking for an apartment to rent.
Looks like you spying in a window.
No, no, no. We're looking for
the owner.
We went around out front
and you trying to squat?
- What's your daddy up to?
- Hey.
Hey,
All right, Mr,
You stay there. Please, miss,
Listen to me.
Don't be scared.
Don't ever be scared.
When I get out of here,
I'm gonna come get you.
Then we'll be together
and we'll never be apart again.
All right? I promise.
I'm sorry, Penny.
I don't know how long this is gonna take,
but when it all gets straightened out,
I'm gonna come get you. I love you.
What do you mean,
come get me, where?
All right, come on.
Please let's go.
Wait. No, please.
I can't leave my Daddy.
Daddy. No, please. No. Daddy, please.
You're okay. Hey, hey, hey.
Don't cry.
Listen to me.
- Daddy. No.
- Don't be scared.
Gotta go.
Daddy. No.
Let's go, miss.
Come on.
Hold on.
I want to see my new hands.
Play baseball, son?
Well, I...
- How about you? Play ball?
- Yes, sir.
Yes sir. Now, that's good.
I don't know what you fuckups did,
but you're lucky to be here.
We aim to make convicts responsible.
Through hard labor and its fruits,
you're gonna get a day off your
sentence for every two days you work.
Good behavior get you out of here on parole
even quicker.
Now, you're gonna work hard,
but you will be paid a daily wage.
Tomorrow's expenses.
Red, you're getting
mighty close to the bone.
You keep chewing.
You see what you find was.
Now, you fuck up,
and this goes for all of you.
And you fuck up and you will find yourself back
in the penitentiary with your time extended
and my boot mark permanently
tattooed on your ass.
- Comprende?
- Yes, sir.
Let's build a rope.
Hey, the cars ain't changing.
You can. You can stare
at them all you want,
but you. You got a shit or
you got to get off the pot.
Can't you see it? Singh,
You can't win. Okay?
Not the same, actually.
Not in this country.
How is it you did not get put in a
colored bunk house where you belong?
- Just ignorant white folk.
- White folk?
But ain't ignorant?
Well, according to the white
folk who run this operation,
I'm technically Caucasian,
Just like you, Rankin.
I fold.
Well, tough luck, comrade.
And you're not like me because I'm white.
And I'm still in the game.
There's a difference.
Hey. Hey, what you think, Murphy?
You think. You think
white folk are ignorant?
I mean, come on.
Singh out here,
he's calling white folks ignorant.
You gonna defend yourself?
What? Yeah. Deal.
Oh, that's.
- That's the dead man's hand.
- Dead man's hand?
Story goes old Wild Bill Hickok,
he got shot right
in the back of the head like that. Yeah.
Trying to play this hand.
- Oh, no, It's. It's not funny.
- No,
You do whatever you want, big country.
But.
I'm all in.
- Bluffing.
- What?
He talks. Wow.
What you know about it, pops?
You even play poker?
No, you just gotta know
when somebody's full of shit.
Maybe Murphy's right.
Not Call.
- All right, what you got?
- I-I have that one
Fuck!
- Do I win it?
- I thought you said he was bluffing.
I just said you got to know
when somebody's full of shit.
I thought that was the same thing, but.
Well, we had a lot of chickens in my farm,
and, you know, for the sheeps, you know,
we wouldn't have a fence around the farm.
So basically we would.
We would kind of teach
them where they need to go.
If one sheep was. Was not in the area,
the sheep was.
Right. The sheep's gone.
- The sheep's. Sheep's gone.
- We shoot it.
Yeah, like a normal farm.
I thought this story about chickens.
What? No.
Everybody, listen up.
Hey, you boys, you like a day off, don't
you?
Yeah, sure you do.
Get the rest up, clean up.
Most importantly, play some baseball.
Playoffs tomorrow.
Teams Are tied.
You man a one game from glory.
Go Pirates.
However, we got ourselves a problem.
So let me tell you the
procedure for this afternoon.
Bob tells me we got a rock up
there needs to be blasted.
But we don't get no more dynamite till Monday.
Powder house is empty.
But I say that rock
has gotta move today.
And if it ain't,
y' all be back out here tomorrow.
There will be no game.
Pirates will forfeit.
- Do you understand me?
- Yes, sir.
So go move that goddamn rock.
Jesus hates Christ. Look at these assholes.
They don't stand a chance.
Hercules couldn't move that rock.
What's wrong with you, Murphy?
Not a team player?
Depends on the team.
You don't mind working out here tomorrow?
I don't much care for Sundays.
Just as soon be earning my two
for one days.
Early release. I like to work.
Yeah, well, me,
I like baseball.
And I love Sundays.
That's the Lord's day.
If we got to be out here tomorrow working,
it ain't gonna be no good time.
I can tell you that right now.
Hey, it's about time.
What are you gonna do, put tires on it?
Christ, Rankin, shut up and dig.
All right, listen. Listen to me
Singh.. I need a 6 in hole right there.
Oh, come in.
See that, right there.
Keep going. Keep going. Keep going.
Keep going. Keep going.
All right. You got the holes?
- Yeah.
- Listen to me. Listen to me.
Shovel. Put it right in there.
Pickaxe. Right in there. All right.
Only these men push. All right?
Nobody else.
So the handles will break
when it moves.
Don't let it stop.
Go.
- Go. Ready?
- Yeah.
Steady. Steady.
Keep. Keep it up.
Don't stop. Don't stop.
Keep moving!
Come on in.
I'm out back.
There he is.
Hercules.
Yeah, that was some fun, Murphy.
Seeing those boys faces.
They were moving heaven and earth
and they couldn't work out how.
Dr. Pepper.
Help yourself.
Pull.
God damn. Murphy.
Murphy. I've never seen that before.
Usually a man will let them fly out a little.
Give them a sporting chance.
Just thought you were supposed to kill 'em
Well, you did that.
Clean these babies up
and you and I are gonna eat.
I don't know if you like cars.
This here's the latest and greatest.
Model 18.
Not working right now, but she's pretty.
- Can I take a look?
- Go ahead.
What's wrong with it?
Pulls left, runs hot.
Don't lack hills and can't break for shit.
- I can fix it.
- Yeah? Which part?
All of it.
We was guarding a cat house in Paris.
The whole damn time
I've been Portland Police Bureau ppp.
So they just put me straight
in the military police.
Our job was trying to
stop doughboys like you
from getting themselves venereal diseases.
Did okay with that for a while.
Till it was the MPs getting the PD.
How about you?
How'd you get them scars?
Oh, Germans were trying to
get position behind us.
My unit was temporarily under
British and French command.
They scouts thought it would improve
our position if I got us up there first.
And I did. And I got these to show for it.
Kind of makes you a war hero. Done it.
Just lucky, I guess.
Wait. These new bearings are all packed.
The Babbitt metal should last for a while.
It won't pull anymore.
Yeah, she was in rough shape.
The fella I got it from ran it hard.
He's retired now,
doing 15 to 20 in Joliet. Yeah,
retired rum runner, huh?
Switches in the dash, modified suspension.
Dirt plate, engines all hopped up,
kind of half assed.
That's why it ran so hot.
Well, well, well.
Man knows a liquor hole in car
when he sees one.
I think I'm gonna learn
to like you, Murphy.
You got any family?
Yeah, got a daughter.
You got good people looking after her?
Problem shared is a burden halved.
So what's the problem, son?
I'm in here.
She's in a home house of the good shepherd.
In one month she'll be awarded
state and up for adoption.
Even with good time I'm in here
six more months.
That's my problem.
Thank you.
Hey murphy.
Done good work. I appreciate it.
She's running real good now.
Tell you the truth,
I didn't come out here just for the joyride.
I've been thinking about you
and your predicament.
If I can get you out here for the end of
the month.
- You like that?
- Can you do that?
Son, out here I do what I want.
I signed the paper
saying your time is done.
Your time is done.
Now this here is gonna be the procedure.
I have a friend who needs a little help.
He's also in a kind of predicament.
He's gonna need four strong men
men he can trust.
I don't trust any of these boys.
But you know them better than I.
And I trust you.
So you have to be in charge.
Now. This ain't gonna be
no picnic like here.
Might get rough.
However, there's good money in it.
Just can't be no fuck ups.
There won't be.
All right. You do this thing.
I will sign the papers for you
and the men you choose.
We got a deal.
Whatever this job is,
it's gonna be illegal.
Look, just asked me to find three
trustworthy men.
I could only find two. And you
guys can seem to like him.
Thank God we're not going on that thing.
Two hours up the mine, give or take.
I don't want to hear Jack Diddly
out of any of you convicts, you hear?
Never been on an airplane before.
What the fuck, Did I just say.
Come on through, Mr. Amis.
Come on, hurry up.
Come on in the desk.
Shut up.
Evening, gentlemen.
George Taggert.
- Which one of you fellas is Murphy?
- Right here. Yeah.
Clancy had nothing but good
words to say about you, Mr. Murphy.
He says you were the man for the job,
which is grand.
Because this job
needs the right man.
The right man.
Now, there is one thing I want you to
know, and it's very important.
See this?
This here is trouble.
Finding it, mining it, particularly,
holding onto it is trouble.
People get funny around gold.
I've seen it.
They'll lie, cheat.
They'll kill you for it.
You hear?
- You hear?
- Sir?
Good. Two weeks from today,
every mine in this country
is getting closed down
and every bit of gold
confiscated, courtesy of FDR.
Yeah. Desperate times.
There are a lot of desperate folk around
who think maybe this gold
ought to belong to them
instead of the US Government.
Two mines in this county already
got looted by their own guards.
Anybody who tried to
protect the vault, got shot.
I trust two men.
And in this place.
And they hear rumblings
and maybe we're up next.
That ain't happening on my watch.
Ain't happening in this mine
because there isn't going to be no gold.
That is because you
men are going to have it.
And first thing
tomorrow morning,
you're going to march it across the
wilderness in the opposite direction
from them animals out there
before anybody even notices. It's gone!
around 50 odd miles
and that hall road you came in on
finally breaks around, joins up again.
Far side of the lake.
That's where we're going to meet.
Six days from now.
Exactly.
Mr. Amis and Mr. Letender will be on
hand to make sure you all don't get lost.
You understand that?
Do you understand that?
Yes, sir.
See, this ain't my gold.
I wish it was, but it ain't.
It belongs to the men who own this mine.
I-I just get paid to protect it.
When do we, get paid?
When you deliver.
You hold up your end and I hold up mine.
All of this gold, and I mean every
last ounce of it, gets to where it's going.
But if any of it goes
missing for any reason,
well, then you got trouble.
Hear me?
- Sir.
Good.
Get out of here.
Anybody taking gold out of here,
it can't look like me and him.
So if we do get caught,
you get shot.
All right,
All right. Come on.
Let's go. Let's go. Come on.
Somebody else is out here.
I don't think so.
Yeah, well, if they are, this whole thing's
going to be over before it gets started.
Are you walking with the rest of them?
Just give me your knife.
- Give me your pack.
- Happily.
What the fuck.
- What's the servant girl doing here?
- Keep it down, man.
Give me that knife.
Anybody with you?
No, I'm alone.
Oh. You better tell me quick
what you're doing out here.
Same as you.
Except for the stealing gold part.
And we ain't stealing nothing.
- We're just trying to...
- Look, I just saw people sneaking out.
I saw the packs.
I needed to get out of that place,
so I figured I'd join 'em.
I can help you.
I'm as strong as any man here.
All right, take it easy.
We can't keep talking.
We have to move.
Who asked you?
- I'm in charge
- None of my business.
Whatever you're doing,
whatever you took.
But I'm not going back.
Okay, we'll just leave her here.
I mean, she can't come with us.
I might get caught if I go back.
Got him.
- Let's go.
- Got him?
No. That's it. Fucking silent...
Worse than these goddamn packs.
How about Pops?
You got any...
You got any stories about the...
The good old days?
Really? Oh, wow
That is. That's interesting.
See, I. I didn't know that.
That is. That's fascinating.
That is very fascinating.
You should tell us more about that.
You know what? Singh. I would even...
I mean, I would even listen to
one of your lectures on the...
What's it called?
The-The history of Coy label.
Maybe later for the evils of capitalism.
- No, you know what, Singh? Hey.
- What?
You should tell these boys
how you got arrested.
- Uh-huh.
- It's a good story.
Singh here, he was arrested
for being a socialist.
Yeah. Accurate as always.
Yep.
I ain't talking.
Come on, Singh...
Come on,
Let's hear it.
First of all, Rankin,
You can't, You can't be arrested
for being a socialist.
- Yeah, you can.
- No, no.
I was convicted for resisting arrest.
I was leading a protest with the
unemployed council.
People got riled up.
Police came in to shut us down,
and one thing leads to another.
Got a little extra
special attention, though,
for the color of my skin.
Look, Singh was arrested
for being red and brown.
Yeah, I can't blame them.
I mean, I wouldn't mind.
They shipped you all out.
Oh, God.
Mouthing off the cops.
Whoa.
Hey. We got a real outlaw on
our hands, ladies and gentlemen.
We got a real, real outlaw.
Seriously? How. How did you get so red?
You're so genuinely interested.
How about I quote you a couple
fitting aphorism?
- No. No one wants to hear that.
- It might enlighten you.
Because a social order which allows one
man who does absolutely nothing useful
a massive fortune whilst
millions toil every day
for a pittance is no
basis for civilization.
I am for socialism
because I am for humanity.
- You better watch your mouth, boy.
- Yeah, shut up, Singh.
Don't listen to me.
But you, you'll listen to a man
with a gun in his hand, now won't you?
Old miners who built these knew their business.
I'll tell you.
They transport equipment and animals.
God damn. All right. I thought I was done,
my balls went up in my stomach.
It'll hold a man,
but not carrying these packs.
Nice.
All right, got it. Ready? I'm ready.
Come on, Singh..
Good catch.
Got two left. All right. One,
two, three.
Got it. Murphy, you drop one,
you might as well go over with it,
cuz we'll all be fuck.
That should buck him up.
Shut your...
Oh, my.
Watch your foot.
Good. Pick that up.
All right,
last one. Here it comes.
No, hold on.
Jesus Christ. All right.
Are you kidding me?
- What is wrong with you?
- Sorry.
- All right.
- That's it. That's it.
All right. That was easy.
This will do.
Put them bags right here.
Anna, get to cooking, girl.
I'm getting water.
- You want some help?
- Nope.
- Said I don't need any help.
- Yeah, I can see that.
Don't let him catch you
with that knife.
They won't.
Be careful.
Some of these plants are poisonous.
Amis. Goddamn.
What the fuck?
- The fuck you want?
- out here?
People mind they're business,
but they'll share a meal if they got one.
Smells good.
Should have made a noise or something.
I did, but you all didn't hear me.
On my way back down.
Saw the fire.
Smell that cooking.
Wouldn't have brought any liquor with you.
Been a while since I drank nothing
but creek water.
Don't get company out here much.
There's a few old trappers around.
Loggers, miners.
You know a place of miners? Mostly.
Hey, you got both
kind of engine.
Imagine that.
We ain't try to camp too close
to you.
Be gone in the morning.
Don't mind.
Anybody out here
knows whose claim's who.
If they don't,
they live,
See, You live out here all alone, huh?
Sometimes
Been all over these mountains.
Know every last piece.
Ah, this area here the best, though.
Plenty game.
Plenty gold, if you know how to get it.
Man, them packs look heavy.
Y' all gonna travel a lot, do you?
Well, we got a long hike tomorrow,
- so we best begin.
- You head down river?
- Nope.
- Where you headed, then?
There ain't but a couple ways to go.
I could show you.
Hey, now, hold on.
Hold on.
You had your meal.
Move on out. See you again,
you're a dead man.
Okay, easy. Easy
there, big fella.
- I'm on my way.
- Yeah.
Look, we don't know how many's with him.
We're slow, we're
easy to follow.
I say we cross this river,
cover our tracks.
Yeah, well, I'd feel better if we
just follow the goddamn map.
Yeah, so would I.
But he's not stupid, all right?
Listen to me, Amis. He knew.
What are you?
Fucking coward.
There's a difference between
cowardice and common sense.
You said yourself, these old miners
will live half a year off some tailings.
What do you think they would
do for what we're carrying?
- I am worried.
- Yeah, well, you should be.
Come on. Move.
Maybe some loggers freeing up the jam.
Oh. Let's go. Let's go, let's go.
Move your ass.
Move me?
Move that thing.
Tie yourself,
I got you...
Hey. Hey. Watch them back.
Hold on. Oh.
Where's the rope?
Hey, man. Attack.
You okay?
Hey, Murphy.
Hey, Murphy Hey, hey, hey.
I'm sorry, man. I can't. I can't.
Okay. Sorry.
Hey, come on. One more.
You really put it on me, old man.
I mean, that was an ass whooping.
I can't remember the last time
I got beat like that.
Kind of fun. You know,
I-I used to fight every day in juvie.
I kind of miss it,
but some places they're tough.
Real tough.
I wouldn't want to be there nowadays.
That looks like it hurts,
Amis. You still have those wire cutters?
Jesus, Murphy.
Might have to cut that finger off.
Okay, hold still now.
This will hurt.
Now you can keep the finger and the ring.
- Thank you.
- That's twice today,
Anna. Quit nursing and cook something up.
- Yeah. I'm hungry.
- No, we can't have a fire.
- What?
- I wouldn't make a fire. Oh.
Oh, you're still scared
about that little old miner.
Yeah,
I crossed your stupid river already for no
goddamn reason.
I've been soaked all day,
so I'm making a fire.
No, I wouldn't do it.
You know what, Murphy?
If you're so fucking smart,
what are you doing out here?
You're just an old convict
who's got a broken hand.
And you don't know shit about shit.
Come on, big country.
I told my story. Singh told his.
Why don't you tell everyone
how you found yourself
carrying gold in the wilderness?
Tell them how you hung that judge.
We ain't playing baseball tomorrow,
Rankin. I didn't hang a judge.
Let it rest.
I think it's a good story.
Go ahead. Also, let's hear it.
I didn't almost hang him.
But he did almost get hung.
What happened
was a judge who kept
foreclosing farm mortgages
on Scandinavian families like he. Like he enjoyed it.
And other judges would
find a way to avoid it.
But not this one.
The God farm along with the others.
We had no way to stop it really.
When you take away a man's ability
to feed his family,
he gets desperate.
And a desperate man,
that's a violent man.
So a group of us all went down
to his cordon, dragged him outside,
had a rope around his neck
and started hanging him.
Most folks thought he deserved it.
Didn't get that far though.
Telling you, you better be careful
he don't make a play on you.
Carry that gold off by himself back to his
uncle's dirt farm.
Frankie, you might just be the most
annoying man I ever met.
You know that?
Told it better last it.
About you lie tender.
All the gold in them packs,
how much you think it's worth?
I'd say it's about...
none of your fucking business.
I mean, ain't you two just
a little worried?
About what?
huh? We get to jump on you and take it?
You spend as much time in the PPB as I did,
you don't worry about little
two bit criminals like you.
I reckon it's worth about a
hundred thousand dollars dollars.
Wow. Of course,
once Roosevelt collects all that gold
in America over the next couple weeks,
well then it's going to be worth
whatever he says is worth.
Franklin Rosevelt and his Jew bankers,
huh? Yeah. And whoever has
that gold could speculate on it.
Well, he stands to make a whole
lot of bread all for doing nothing.
Cause well, that's the American way.
- Shut up.
- Yeah, shut up, Singh.
What you know about it?
It's in the newspaper, Rankin. All right,
I read. Debs, Darrow,
Payne. Bunch of bullshit.
Hey. Hey. Wake up. Wake up.
Murph. I think we got a problem.
There's boats down there tied up on
the bank.
They're empty.
- How many?
- Two
Let's go. Everybody up. Backs on
them both. Could have just been there. No,
it's him. Good.
If it is him, then enemies.
Buddy's about to be dead.
No, we are about to be dead.
If there are
two boats, that means more than two men.
We're sitting in a
shooting gallery right here.
Singh.. Yeah. Right back
from where you came.
Letender, go with them.
No. Why are we going to the river?
Because we're taking their boats.
All right, now I gotta move you over.
I gotta see the back.
I gotta see if it came out.
Yeah, I gotta do it. Gotta see.
Gotta see the other side.
All right. All right.
Good. Came out all right.
Okay. Wow. All right.
Came out the other side.
Yeah, that's good. That's good.
Allright, now I gotta make a tourniquet.
Just lift up for a second.
is it all right?
Yeah. Count to three. One.
We're gonna have to take
a look at your back, too,
when we stop.
How you doing, big boy?
You gonna be able to walk?
Yeah, he's fine.
Hey, hey, hey. Listen to me.
What are you doing when you get out?
I'm kiss my wife and my boys.
- How many boys do you have?
- Two, Sir
You miss 'em?
I miss my daughter.
- You got a daughter?
- hmm.
Be glad to see him.
She with her mama?
She's at a. She's at home,
you know, at school.
That's why I write her every day.
Just to let her know
I'm thinking about her.
Look at me. Look at me.
- You're gonna be fine. Okay?
- Okay.
Might get you a cane for Christmas,
but you're going to be fine.
Get them packs up here.
All right. Let's unload.
Yeah. You stay. You stay down.
I'll be right back.
Okay. Oh, God Damn it.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
I got you some water, all right?
Okay. Okay. Sorry.
I'll sit with you. Okay.
Give me your hand.
Shotgun pellets found you.
But he was pretty far away,
so it's not too bad.
Yeah. Broke the skin in a few places.
Take this. Just rub
it on good and let it sit.
What's it do? It's for infection.
Like this? Yes.
What you said about your daughter today.
I was all alone
in this school growing up, too.
It was like a military school.
They were teaching me
how to be a servant in Anglo homes.
Their motto was,
kill the Indian, save the man.
Didn't interest me much, so.
I ran away.
Did they?
What?
Killed the indian, I mean.
They didn't kill anything in me,
they didn't save anything either.
I think I saw something last night.
I couldn't sleep and I just looked up
and it was right next to him.
Looks like they were.
They were choking them,
smothering them or something.
Could you tell for sure?
I couldn't see for sure,
but it. It didn't look right.
All I know is it went in to kill him today.
Or we end up like him.
Okay. We're not doing
Anybody tries, you won't have to worry
about Amis, Letender.
Cuz I'll kill you.
Amis
Yeah. You see anything?
Notice anything last night,
before Olson died?
Well, yeah.
I heard him call out,
went over to check up on him.
He was in rough shape.
Looked like he couldn't breathe.
Was trying to say something.
Leaned down, got close to him.
Then he got still again.
I just let him be
and prayed he was gonna be all right.
All right. Drop me here.
Taggert should be here by dawn.
- We made it, huh?
- We'll see.
Whiskeys, fine.
- It should be. It was Taggert.
- Is that right?
Here's to George Taggert.
A more equitable distribution of goods.
Why don't you come home with me tomorrow?
You can cook.
I'll provide for you.
You like that, huh?
What you think, girl?
Yeah.
I think men who talk big usually ain't big.
Sleep tight, boys.
Daddy. Daddy. Daddy.
Daddy. Daddy.
You fuck, now.
Look at you. You ain't worth shit.
Come down here.
So this is your girlfriend?
All you do is save me the trouble of
killing you later with the rest of them.
Now, you're dead, man.
Hey. Hey.
What's the plan?
You ain't getting your
kid back if you're dead.
I told you it was a dirty deal.
Hey, we need to get the gold
and we need to move. Yeah.
He said they were gonna kill us.
And I ain't dying in these woods.
Come on, baby. Come on. What's the plan?
Please. Come on.
Here we go. Here we go.
Hey, wake up.
Amis. Get up.
Where is everybody, huh?
Come on, wake up. Get up.
Get up and load them pecks on the
truck now.
- Move it. Move!
- Sir. Sir. Sir.
Get moving. Come on.
Amis, where is everybody?
Where's Letender?
What? What the fuck Amis? You're asking me?
Get the packs on the goddamn truck.
If this doesn't go right,
you get back down in that coach
and you follow it up river.
I'm pretty sure it crosses that same access road
that you just drove up out.
But don't leave too early.
You got that?
Do not leave too early.
They're not going to hang
around long with all that gold,
but they're going to be
looking for you.
All right.
Just stay in the woods till after dark.
You shut your mouth.
You hear me? Come on. Pick it up.
I'm going to. I'm going.
Want to get smart with me, huh?
Let's hold it back.
Hey, Taggert. Yeah?
You said that walk was going to be hard.
We got here early. Yeah,
Well, like I said, Murphy,
you're the man for the job.
Oh, thanks. I appreciate that.
Really do.
Say, where is everybody?
I don't know.
Letender.
He's. He's taking a shit.
You know him?
He's gonna be a while.
But he was saying.
I mean, I don't know what you think,
but he was saying maybe we deserve a bonus.
You know, I don't know
how you feel about that.
Sure. Now, let's talk about that.
Murphy, you hold it right there.
All right? When I move, you go, go, go, go.
Oh. shit.
All right. Beautiful.
Yeah. Come on.
I got you now.
I get you now. I got you.
Come on.
- Murphy.
- Clancy.
Help myself.
Looks like you deserve it.
I thought things were gonna get rough out there.
You okay, son?
I'm great.
Well, I told Taggert you'd get the job done.
Where is he?
He's not coming.
Let's go inside.
Dark business.
Get you something stronger to drink.
You want that drink?
We're not here for hospitality.
What about you, missy?
You want a drink?
- No.
- Whatever y' all need.
What's mine is yours.
After all,
we're all on the same team.
This was Taggert's pistol.
That one there belonged to Amis.
It's the same model you carry.
Now, I don't know what team you all play for,
but it sure as hell ain't mine.
I don't know what happened out there,
but if that's what I think it is,
y' all better listen to me
and listen to me good.
That there is stolen government gold.
You don't want to be tied to it,
and you don't want to be
tied to no murder, neither.
So you leave it here.
We'll lock it in the office overnight,
and
tomorrow I'll get it to where it's going.
Then I will sign your papers,
arrange your transportation out of here,
and y' all be free man,
That was the deal.
Can't you see it?
You got a bad hand,
- Clancy.
- No, he's right.
He's right. We don't want to be tied to it.
But the only one
who can tie us to it is you.
Every other man who saw us come in
and out of that mine is dead.
And nobody's gonna find them.
We made sure of that.
Of course they're missing.
And the gold's missing.
That's suspicious.
Yeah. A good cop,
he would track this gold down
till it was safe in some government vault somewhere.
And he'd bring those
thieves to justice.
But a-a bad cop,
he might want that gold to just disappear.
Along with the mystery of what
happened to Taggert and the boys.
You know what your friend Taggert
said to me right before he died?
He asked me if I wanted
your share of the gold.
He didn't get it.
I don't want your share.
I want my daughter.
So here's the procedure.
Rankin, Anna, Singh,
Olson's family, me and you,
we're gonna split the gold even.
Cause when I leave here, I don't
want to be worried about you.
And I know you don't want to be
worried about me.
So you sign those papers
and you get your gold.
And then I will go get my daughter.
Oh, yeah, one more thing.
Do you have the registration for that 418.
I like that car.
You ready?
I've been over these papers a
hundred times.
Yeah. I'm ready.
Don't worry.
Mrs. Akers.
Mr. Murphy,
I told you I had never been caught.
And I ain't never gonna be caught.
"Call Me the Breeze - Lynyrd Skynyrd" playing
♪ Call me the breeze ♪
♪ I keep blowing down the road. ♪
♪ Well, now they call me the breeze ♪
♪ I ain't got me nobody. ♪
♪ I don't carry me no load ♪
♪ Ain't no change in the weather ♪
♪ Ain't no changes in me ♪
♪ Well, there ain't no change in the weather ♪
♪ And I ain't hidin' from nobody ♪
♪ Nobody's hidin' from me ♪
♪ Oh, that's the way it's supposed to be ♪
♪ Well, I got that green light, baby ♪
♪ I got keep movin' on. ♪
♪ Well, I might go out to California ♪
♪ Might go down to Georgia ♪
♪ I don't know. ♪
♪ Well, now they call me the breeze ♪
♪ I keep blowin' down the road ♪
♪ I ain't got me nobody. ♪
♪ I don't carry me no load ♪
♪ Ooh, Mr. Breeze ♪